Jay Fallon - UX Designer & Engineer

One Canal St., #431, Boston MA 02114 617-460-7516 - jayfallon@gmail.com - https://jayfallon.net

Summary

Jay Fallon is a User Experience professional with years of experience in product design and development for a list of clients that includes large enterprises, small businesses and start-up ventures. Jay's interests lie in customer focused application design and development, rapid and iterative prototyping, user-centric design and testing methodologies, the responsive experience and courseware design production and learning management systems.

Technical Skills

User experience design, interaction design, information architecture, usability testing, front-end architecture and development to include modern responsive design, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React (including React Native, Next.js, Gatsby.js), jQuery, AngularJS, GraphQL, Node/Express, JSX, Jade/Pug, Styled Components, PostCSS, Sass/Scss, LESS, Stylus, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Git, Python, Ruby/Rails, Java-based frameworks, Adobe Experience Manager; audio-visual creation and design to include Sketch, InVision, OmniGraffle, Framer, Adobe Premiere, After Effects, Illustrator, Photoshop and Audition. Agile methodologies. Fluent in English and Spanish.

Education

Harvard University Extension School, Cambridge MA.

Master of Liberal Arts, Digital Design, May 2019

Concentration in Digital Design, with coursework in information systems, software development, instructional design and digital production.

Northeastern University, Boston MA.

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, June 1998

Majored in International Business and Finance. Completed cooperative education assignments at Boston's Better Snacks, FMRC and PictureTel with learning opportunities and responsibilities in operations, marketing, technical documentation and internationalization.

Experience

Senior UX/UI Developer; State Street Global Advisors, Inc., Boston, MA

April 2019 - Present

As a UX developer, Jay works to support SSgA's global digital team's efforts to implement digital transformation initiatives by providing design and development deliverables, consultation and oversight as they migrate their content offering to Adobe Experience Manager.

Senior UX/UI Developer; Syrinx Consulting, Boston MA.

June 2018 - March 2019

As a UI/UX developer for a Syrinx client, Jay is responsible for providing leadership, technical direction, mentoring, training and support for a fifty-person research department focused on enhancing the client's future capabilities in personalized customer experience. In this role, Jay provides research, testing, selection and implementation of front end technologies in order to properly architect solutions that will integrate with existing customer data to transform the client's existing web and data strategies.

UX Designer and Developer; James Fallon Consulting, Boston, MA.

September 2009 - December 2010, March 2012 - March 2013, June 2016 - June 2018 Responsible for assisting clients with web-based strategies, product research, design and development. Project engagements include working with Style Me Pretty on their upcoming website release, a ground-up overhaul of their existing products. Jay's responsibilities included working closely with the client to craft and implement a comprehensive experience strategy in addition to providing research, design and demonstration deliverables.

UX Designer and Developer; Cengage Learning, Boston, MA.

March 2014 - June 2016

Created an in-house CSS framework and reusable component library, provided design direction and development on multiple Cengage projects that included legacy code conversion, cross-platform CSS standardization, component design and user testing. In addition to his day to day responsibilities, Jay worked alongside senior management to define design and technical requirements for future platform releases.

Software Engineer, UX Designer; Boston Technologies, Inc., Boston, MA.

December 2010 - March 2012

Working in conjunction with a development team, Jay was responsible for the user experience and front-end architecture, design and development on a foreign exchange trading platform. Duties included research, development and testing for both internal and external product offerings in the form of web-based dashboards, trading applications and analysis.

UX Developer; State Street Global Advisors, Inc., Boston, MA.

June 2007 - September 2008

As a consultant, Jay worked closely with multiple internal teams on projects requiring design, development and ongoing maintenance for existing, new and transitioning web-based products. Jay's responsibilities included the design, production and deployment of deliverables along with providing testing and technical support.

UX Designer and Developer; netNumina Solutions, Inc., Cambridge, MA

June 2000 - December 2006

Duties include providing technical expertise to account managers, user experience and development teams as well as executing the user experience requirements into deliverables for integration with web applications or standalone websites. Client list includes Fidelity Management & Resource Company, State Street Global Advisors, Johnson & Johnson, Pfizer and ADQSR.